<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>SlashDevOps</title>
    <link>https://slashdevops.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on SlashDevOps</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2024 10:17:23 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://slashdevops.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Using Files as a Flag in the Golang Command Line Interface (CLI)</title>
      <link>https://slashdevops.com/post/2024/04/07/1/using-files-as-a-flag-in-the-golang-command-line-interface-cli/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2024 10:17:23 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://slashdevops.com/post/2024/04/07/1/using-files-as-a-flag-in-the-golang-command-line-interface-cli/</guid>
      <description>Introduction In this post, we will see how to use files as a flag in the Golang Command Line Interface (CLI). This is useful when you want to pass a file (not the file name, but an object of file type) as a flag to your CLI application.
Use the file name as a flag is straightforward, you can use the flag.String or flag.StringVar function to get the file name and then do the necessary checks to validate if this exist, create it, clean it, etc.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building and Debugging a C Project in Visual Studio Code with a Makefile</title>
      <link>https://slashdevops.com/post/2024/03/31/2/building-and-debugging-a-c-project-in-visual-studio-code-with-a-makefile/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2024 20:02:45 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://slashdevops.com/post/2024/03/31/2/building-and-debugging-a-c-project-in-visual-studio-code-with-a-makefile/</guid>
      <description>Introduction I have been using Visual Studio Code (vscode) for my C language projects until I&amp;rsquo;m re-learning this powerful programming language. One of the features that I like about vscode is the ability to build and debug C language projects using a Makefile. In this post, I will show you how to build and debug a C project in vscode using a Makefile.
also, I built a GitHub repository template for this project called c-library-template, where you can use it to create a new C project with the following features:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Migrated from WordPress to Hugo and GitHub Pages</title>
      <link>https://slashdevops.com/post/2024/03/31/1/migrated-from-wordpress-to-hugo-and-github-pages/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2024 13:25:51 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://slashdevops.com/post/2024/03/31/1/migrated-from-wordpress-to-hugo-and-github-pages/</guid>
      <description>Introduction I have been using WordPress for a long time to host slashdevops.com blog site. I had been looking for a way to migrate this blog from WordPress to a static site generator and during the research I found Hugo and I can say I am very happy with it. Hugo allows me to write this blog posts in Markdown and it is very fast and easy to use.
I have also been using GitHub Pages for other of my personal jobs and I decided to migrate this blog GitHub Pages as well.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Secure and Easy AWS Connection Assuming a Role With Jenkins Shared Library</title>
      <link>https://slashdevops.com/post/2022/12/03/1/secure-and-easy-aws-connection-assuming-a-role-with-jenkins-shared-library/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Dec 2022 20:39:29 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://slashdevops.com/post/2022/12/03/1/secure-and-easy-aws-connection-assuming-a-role-with-jenkins-shared-library/</guid>
      <description>How to connect to AWS Account assuming a role with Jenkins shared library</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My custom MacBook Pro [m1|m2] Provisioning</title>
      <link>https://slashdevops.com/post/2022/09/17/1/my-custom-macbook-ro-m1-m2-provisioning/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Sep 2022 21:12:43 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://slashdevops.com/post/2022/09/17/1/my-custom-macbook-ro-m1-m2-provisioning/</guid>
      <description>How I provision my MacBook Pro [m1|m2] with my custom scripts</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Managing the Lifecycle of your Elasticsearch Indices</title>
      <link>https://slashdevops.com/post/2020/05/13/1/managing-the-lifecycle-of-your-elasticsearch-indices/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 May 2020 17:59:22 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://slashdevops.com/post/2020/05/13/1/managing-the-lifecycle-of-your-elasticsearch-indices/</guid>
      <description>How to efficiently manage index lifecycles in an automated and clean manner</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
